Four walls. One faith. No identity.
Song for a Raggy Boy is a drama, history film directed by Aisling Walsh.
William Franklin is a teacher who was born in Ireland and moved to the United States only to
repatriate in 1939 after his leftist political views cause him to lose his job.
Franklin becomes the first non-cleric instructor at St.
Jude's, a school for wayward boys run by Brother John, who
is a firm believer in strong discipline.
William Franklin, played by Aidan Quinn.
Brother John, played by Iain Glen.
Brother Mac, played by Marc Warren.
Brother Tom, played by Dudley Sutton.
Father Damian, played by Alan Devlin.
Brother Whelan, played by Stuart Graham.
Song for a Raggy Boy is a 2003 Irish historical drama film directed by Aisling Walsh who co-wrote the screenplay with Kevin Byron
Murphy and based on the 1991 autobiographical book of the same name by Patrick Galvin and heavily inspired by true events.
The film stars Aidan Quinn, Iain Glen, Chris
Newman, Marc Warren and John Travers.
Set in 1939 Ireland, on the brink of World War II, the film takes place in St.
Jude’s Reformatory School, a harsh Catholic institution for troubled
and orphaned boys run by the Irish Christian Brothers.
The story follows William Franklin (Quinn), the school’s only lay (non-religious) teacher and a veteran of the Spanish Civil War who is
haunted by his past, who arrives with progressive teaching ideas and a belief in treating the boys with kindness and respect.
After being appalled by the brutal, authoritarian regime of the school, particularly with the cruel Brother John (Glen), who believes in discipline
through physical punishment, and the more complex, conflicted Brother Mac (Warren), he must fights to liberate the boys from their oppressors.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
poetry, beating, reformatory, strap.
The tone is emotional.